<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<c n="11">
      <v n="1">Then answered Zophar the Naamathite, and said,</v>
      <v n="2">Should not the multitude of words be answered? and should a man full of talk be justified? {full...: Heb. of lips}</v>
      <v n="3">Should thy lies make men hold their peace? and when thou mockest, shall no man make thee ashamed? {lies: or, devices}</v>
      <v n="4">For thou hast said, My doctrine {is} pure, and I am clean in thine eyes.</v>
      <v n="5">But oh that God would speak, and open his lips against thee;</v>
      <v n="6">And that he would shew thee the secrets of wisdom, that {they are} double to that which is! Know therefore that God exacteth of thee {less} than thine iniquity {deserveth}.</v>
      <v n="7">Canst thou by searching find out God? canst thou find out the Almighty unto perfection?</v>
      <v n="8">{It is} as high as heaven; what canst thou do? deeper than hell; what canst thou know? {as high...: Heb. the heights of heaven}</v>
      <v n="9">The measure thereof {is} longer than the earth, and broader than the sea.</v>
      <v n="10">If he cut off, and shut up, or gather together, then who can hinder him? {cut...: or, make a change} {hinder...: Heb. turn him away?}</v>
      <v n="11">For he knoweth vain men: he seeth wickedness also; will he not then consider {it}?</v>
      <v n="12">For vain man would be wise, though man be born {like} a wild ass's colt. {vain: Heb. empty}</v>
      <v n="13">If thou prepare thine heart, and stretch out thine hands toward him;</v>
      <v n="14">If iniquity {be} in thine hand, put it far away, and let not wickedness dwell in thy tabernacles.</v>
      <v n="15">For then shalt thou lift up thy face without spot; yea, thou shalt be stedfast, and shalt not fear:</v>
      <v n="16">Because thou shalt forget {thy} misery, {and} remember {it} as waters {that} pass away:</v>
      <v n="17">And {thine} age shall be clearer than the noonday; thou shalt shine forth, thou shalt be as the morning. {be clearer...: Heb. arise above}</v>
      <v n="18">And thou shalt be secure, because there is hope; yea, thou shalt dig {about thee, and} thou shalt take thy rest in safety.</v>
      <v n="19">Also thou shalt lie down, and none shall make {thee} afraid; yea, many shall make suit unto thee. {make suit...: Heb. intreat thy face}</v>
      <v n="20">But the eyes of the wicked shall fail, and they shall not escape, and their hope {shall be as} the giving up of the ghost. {they shall...: Heb. flight shall perish from them} {the giving...: or, a puff of breath}</v>
    </c>
