<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<c n="4">
      <v n="1">Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered and said,</v>
      <v n="2">{If} we assay to commune with thee, wilt thou be grieved? but who can withhold himself from speaking? {to...: Heb. a word} {withhold...: Heb. refrain from words?}</v>
      <v n="3">Behold, thou hast instructed many, and thou hast strengthened the weak hands.</v>
      <v n="4">Thy words have upholden him that was falling, and thou hast strengthened the feeble knees.</v>
      <v n="5">But now it is come upon thee, and thou faintest; it toucheth thee, and thou art troubled.</v>
      <v n="6">{Is} not {this} thy fear, thy confidence, thy hope, and the uprightness of thy ways?</v>
      <v n="7">Remember, I pray thee, who {ever} perished, being innocent? or where were the righteous cut off?</v>
      <v n="8">Even as I have seen, they that plow iniquity, and sow wickedness, reap the same.</v>
      <v n="9">By the blast of God they perish, and by the breath of his nostrils are they consumed. {by the breath...: that is, by his anger}</v>
      <v n="10">The roaring of the lion, and the voice of the fierce lion, and the teeth of the young lions, are broken.</v>
      <v n="11">The old lion perisheth for lack of prey, and the stout lion's whelps are scattered abroad.</v>
      <v n="12">Now a thing was secretly brought to me, and mine ear received a little thereof. {secretly: Heb. by stealth}</v>
      <v n="13">In thoughts from the visions of the night, when deep sleep falleth on men,</v>
      <v n="14">Fear came upon me, and trembling, which made all my bones to shake. {came...: Heb. met} {all: Heb. the multitude of}</v>
      <v n="15">Then a spirit passed before my face; the hair of my flesh stood up:</v>
      <v n="16">It stood still, but I could not discern the form thereof: an image {was} before mine eyes, {there was} silence, and I heard a voice, {saying}, {there...: or, I heard a still voice}</v>
      <v n="17">Shall mortal man be more just than God? shall a man be more pure than his maker?</v>
      <v n="18">Behold, he put no trust in his servants; and his angels he charged with folly: {and his...: or, nor in his angels, in whom he put light}</v>
      <v n="19">How much less {in} them that dwell in houses of clay, whose foundation {is} in the dust, {which} are crushed before the moth?</v>
      <v n="20">They are destroyed from morning to evening: they perish for ever without any regarding {it}. {destroyed: Heb. beaten in pieces}</v>
      <v n="21">Doth not their excellency {which is} in them go away? they die, even without wisdom.</v>
    </c>
