<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<c n="27">
      <v n="1">Boast not thyself of to morrow; for thou knowest not what a day may bring forth. {to...: Heb. to morrow day}</v>
      <v n="2">Let another man praise thee, and not thine own mouth; a stranger, and not thine own lips.</v>
      <v n="3">A stone {is} heavy, and the sand weighty; but a fool's wrath {is} heavier than them both. {heavy: Heb. heaviness}</v>
      <v n="4">Wrath {is} cruel, and anger {is} outrageous; but who {is} able to stand before envy? {Wrath...: Heb. Wrath is cruelty, and anger an overflowing} {envy: or, jealousy?}</v>
      <v n="5">Open rebuke {is} better than secret love.</v>
      <v n="6">Faithful {are} the wounds of a friend; but the kisses of an enemy {are} deceitful. {deceitful: or, earnest, or, frequent}</v>
      <v n="7">The full soul loatheth an honeycomb; but to the hungry soul every bitter thing is sweet. {loatheth: Heb. treadeth under foot}</v>
      <v n="8">As a bird that wandereth from her nest, so {is} a man that wandereth from his place.</v>
      <v n="9">Ointment and perfume rejoice the heart: so {doth} the sweetness of a man's friend by hearty counsel. {by...: Heb. from the counsel of the soul}</v>
      <v n="10">Thine own friend, and thy father's friend, forsake not; neither go into thy brother's house in the day of thy calamity: {for} better {is} a neighbour {that is} near than a brother far off.</v>
      <v n="11">My son, be wise, and make my heart glad, that I may answer him that reproacheth me.</v>
      <v n="12">A prudent {man} foreseeth the evil, {and} hideth himself; {but} the simple pass on, {and} are punished.</v>
      <v n="13">Take his garment that is surety for a stranger, and take a pledge of him for a strange woman.</v>
      <v n="14">He that blesseth his friend with a loud voice, rising early in the morning, it shall be counted a curse to him.</v>
      <v n="15">A continual dropping in a very rainy day and a contentious woman are alike.</v>
      <v n="16">Whosoever hideth her hideth the wind, and the ointment of his right hand, {which} bewrayeth {itself}.</v>
      <v n="17">Iron sharpeneth iron; so a man sharpeneth the countenance of his friend.</v>
      <v n="18">Whoso keepeth the fig tree shall eat the fruit thereof: so he that waiteth on his master shall be honoured.</v>
      <v n="19">As in water face {answereth} to face, so the heart of man to man.</v>
      <v n="20">Hell and destruction are never full; so the eyes of man are never satisfied. {never: Heb. not}</v>
      <v n="21">{As} the fining pot for silver, and the furnace for gold; so {is} a man to his praise.</v>
      <v n="22">Though thou shouldest bray a fool in a mortar among wheat with a pestle, {yet} will not his foolishness depart from him.</v>
      <v n="23">Be thou diligent to know the state of thy flocks, {and} look well to thy herds. {look...: Heb. set thy heart}</v>
      <v n="24">For riches {are} not for ever: and doth the crown {endure} to every generation? {riches: Heb. strength} {to...: Heb. to generation and generation?}</v>
      <v n="25">The hay appeareth, and the tender grass sheweth itself, and herbs of the mountains are gathered.</v>
      <v n="26">The lambs {are} for thy clothing, and the goats {are} the price of the field.</v>
      <v n="27">And {thou shalt have} goats' milk enough for thy food, for the food of thy household, and {for} the maintenance for thy maidens. {maintenance: Heb. life}</v>
    </c>
