<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<c n="4">
      <v n="1">So king Solomon was king over all Israel.</v>
      <v n="2">And these {were} the princes which he had; Azariah the son of Zadok the priest, {priest: or, chief officer}</v>
      <v n="3">Elihoreph and Ahiah, the sons of Shisha, scribes; Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud, the recorder. {scribes: or, secretaries} {recorder: or, remembrancer}</v>
      <v n="4">And Benaiah the son of Jehoiada {was} over the host: and Zadok and Abiathar {were} the priests:</v>
      <v n="5">And Azariah the son of Nathan {was} over the officers: and Zabud the son of Nathan {was} principal officer, {and} the king's friend:</v>
      <v n="6">And Ahishar {was} over the household: and Adoniram the son of Abda {was} over the tribute. {tribute: or, levy}</v>
      <v n="7">And Solomon had twelve officers over all Israel, which provided victuals for the king and his household: each man his month in a year made provision.</v>
      <v n="8">And these {are} their names: The son of Hur, in mount Ephraim: {The son...: or, Benhur}</v>
      <v n="9">The son of Dekar, in Makaz, and in Shaalbim, and Bethshemesh, and Elonbethhanan: {The son...: or, Bendekar}</v>
      <v n="10">The son of Hesed, in Aruboth; to him {pertained} Sochoh, and all the land of Hepher: {The son...: or, Benhesed}</v>
      <v n="11">The son of Abinadab, in all the region of Dor; which had Taphath the daughter of Solomon to wife: {The son...: or, Benabinadab}</v>
      <v n="12">Baana the son of Ahilud; {to him pertained} Taanach and Megiddo, and all Bethshean, which {is} by Zartanah beneath Jezreel, from Bethshean to Abelmeholah, {even} unto {the place that is} beyond Jokneam:</v>
      <v n="13">The son of Geber, in Ramothgilead; to him {pertained} the towns of Jair the son of Manasseh, which {are} in Gilead; to him {also pertained} the region of Argob, which {is} in Bashan, threescore great cities with walls and brasen bars: {The son...: or, Bengeber}</v>
      <v n="14">Ahinadab the son of Iddo {had} Mahanaim: {Mahanaim: or, to Mahanaim}</v>
      <v n="15">Ahimaaz {was} in Naphtali; he also took Basmath the daughter of Solomon to wife:</v>
      <v n="16">Baanah the son of Hushai {was} in Asher and in Aloth:</v>
      <v n="17">Jehoshaphat the son of Paruah, in Issachar:</v>
      <v n="18">Shimei the son of Elah, in Benjamin:</v>
      <v n="19">Geber the son of Uri {was} in the country of Gilead, {in} the country of Sihon king of the Amorites, and of Og king of Bashan; and {he was} the only officer which {was} in the land.</v>
      <v n="20">Judah and Israel {were} many, as the sand which {is} by the sea in multitude, eating and drinking, and making merry.</v>
      <v n="21">And Solomon reigned over all kingdoms from the river unto the land of the Philistines, and unto the border of Egypt: they brought presents, and served Solomon all the days of his life.</v>
      <v n="22">And Solomon's provision for one day was thirty measures of fine flour, and threescore measures of meal, {provision: Heb. bread} {measures: Heb. cors}</v>
      <v n="23">Ten fat oxen, and twenty oxen out of the pastures, and an hundred sheep, beside harts, and roebucks, and fallowdeer, and fatted fowl.</v>
      <v n="24">For he had dominion over all {the region} on this side the river, from Tiphsah even to Azzah, over all the kings on this side the river: and he had peace on all sides round about him.</v>
      <v n="25">And Judah and Israel dwelt safely, every man under his vine and under his fig tree, from Dan even to Beersheba, all the days of Solomon. {safely: Heb. confidently}</v>
      <v n="26">And Solomon had forty thousand stalls of horses for his chariots, and twelve thousand horsemen.</v>
      <v n="27">And those officers provided victual for king Solomon, and for all that came unto king Solomon's table, every man in his month: they lacked nothing.</v>
      <v n="28">Barley also and straw for the horses and dromedaries brought they unto the place where {the officers} were, every man according to his charge. {dromedaries: or, mules, or, swift beasts}</v>
      <v n="29">And God gave Solomon wisdom and understanding exceeding much, and largeness of heart, even as the sand that {is} on the sea shore.</v>
      <v n="30">And Solomon's wisdom excelled the wisdom of all the children of the east country, and all the wisdom of Egypt.</v>
      <v n="31">For he was wiser than all men; than Ethan the Ezrahite, and Heman, and Chalcol, and Darda, the sons of Mahol: and his fame was in all nations round about.</v>
      <v n="32">And he spake three thousand proverbs: and his songs were a thousand and five.</v>
      <v n="33">And he spake of trees, from the cedar tree that {is} in Lebanon even unto the hyssop that springeth out of the wall: he spake also of beasts, and of fowl, and of creeping things, and of fishes.</v>
      <v n="34">And there came of all people to hear the wisdom of Solomon, from all kings of the earth, which had heard of his wisdom.</v>
    </c>
