<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<c n="46">
      <v n="1">And Israel took his journey with all that he had, and came to Beersheba, and offered sacrifices unto the God of his father Isaac.</v>
      <v n="2">And God spake unto Israel in the visions of the night, and said, Jacob, Jacob. And he said, Here {am} I.</v>
      <v n="3">And he said, I {am} God, the God of thy father: fear not to go down into Egypt; for I will there make of thee a great nation:</v>
      <v n="4">I will go down with thee into Egypt; and I will also surely bring thee up {again}: and Joseph shall put his hand upon thine eyes.</v>
      <v n="5">And Jacob rose up from Beersheba: and the sons of Israel carried Jacob their father, and their little ones, and their wives, in the wagons which Pharaoh had sent to carry him.</v>
      <v n="6">And they took their cattle, and their goods, which they had gotten in the land of Canaan, and came into Egypt, Jacob, and all his seed with him:</v>
      <v n="7">His sons, and his sons' sons with him, his daughters, and his sons' daughters, and all his seed brought he with him into Egypt.</v>
      <v n="8">And these {are} the names of the children of Israel, which came into Egypt, Jacob and his sons: Reuben, Jacob's firstborn.</v>
      <v n="9">And the sons of Reuben; Hanoch, and Phallu, and Hezron, and Carmi.</v>
      <v n="10">And the sons of Simeon; Jemuel, and Jamin, and Ohad, and Jachin, and Zohar, and Shaul the son of a Canaanitish woman. {Jemuel: or, Nemuel} {Jachin: or, Jarib} {Zohar: or, Zerah}</v>
      <v n="11">And the sons of Levi; Gershon, Kohath, and Merari. {Gershon: or, Gershom}</v>
      <v n="12">And the sons of Judah; Er, and Onan, and Shelah, and Pharez, and Zerah: but Er and Onan died in the land of Canaan. And the sons of Pharez were Hezron and Hamul.</v>
      <v n="13">And the sons of Issachar; Tola, and Phuvah, and Job, and Shimron. {Phuvah, and Job: or, Puah, and Jashub}</v>
      <v n="14">And the sons of Zebulun; Sered, and Elon, and Jahleel.</v>
      <v n="15">These {be} the sons of Leah, which she bare unto Jacob in Padanaram, with his daughter Dinah: all the souls of his sons and his daughters {were} thirty and three.</v>
      <v n="16">And the sons of Gad; Ziphion, and Haggi, Shuni, and Ezbon, Eri, and Arodi, and Areli. {Ziphion: or, Zephon} {Ezbon: or, Ozni} {Arodi: or, Arod}</v>
      <v n="17">And the sons of Asher; Jimnah, and Ishuah, and Isui, and Beriah, and Serah their sister: and the sons of Beriah; Heber, and Malchiel.</v>
      <v n="18">These {are} the sons of Zilpah, whom Laban gave to Leah his daughter, and these she bare unto Jacob, {even} sixteen souls.</v>
      <v n="19">The sons of Rachel Jacob's wife; Joseph, and Benjamin.</v>
      <v n="20">And unto Joseph in the land of Egypt were born Manasseh and Ephraim, which Asenath the daughter of Potipherah priest of On bare unto him. {priest: or, prince}</v>
      <v n="21">And the sons of Benjamin {were} Belah, and Becher, and Ashbel, Gera, and Naaman, Ehi, and Rosh, Muppim, and Huppim, and Ard. {Ehi: or, Ahiram} {Muppim: or, Shupham or, Shuppim} {Huppim: or, Hupham}</v>
      <v n="22">These {are} the sons of Rachel, which were born to Jacob: all the souls {were} fourteen.</v>
      <v n="23">And the sons of Dan; Hushim. {Hushim: or, Shuham}</v>
      <v n="24">And the sons of Naphtali; Jahzeel, and Guni, and Jezer, and Shillem.</v>
      <v n="25">These {are} the sons of Bilhah, which Laban gave unto Rachel his daughter, and she bare these unto Jacob: all the souls {were} seven.</v>
      <v n="26">All the souls that came with Jacob into Egypt, which came out of his loins, besides Jacob's sons' wives, all the souls {were} threescore and six; {loins: Heb. thigh}</v>
      <v n="27">And the sons of Joseph, which were born him in Egypt, {were} two souls: all the souls of the house of Jacob, which came into Egypt, {were} threescore and ten.</v>
      <v n="28">And he sent Judah before him unto Joseph, to direct his face unto Goshen; and they came into the land of Goshen.</v>
      <v n="29">And Joseph made ready his chariot, and went up to meet Israel his father, to Goshen, and presented himself unto him; and he fell on his neck, and wept on his neck a good while.</v>
      <v n="30">And Israel said unto Joseph, Now let me die, since I have seen thy face, because thou {art} yet alive.</v>
      <v n="31">And Joseph said unto his brethren, and unto his father's house, I will go up, and shew Pharaoh, and say unto him, My brethren, and my father's house, which {were} in the land of Canaan, are come unto me;</v>
      <v n="32">And the men {are} shepherds, for their trade hath been to feed cattle; and they have brought their flocks, and their herds, and all that they have. {their trade...: Heb. they are men of cattle}</v>
      <v n="33">And it shall come to pass, when Pharaoh shall call you, and shall say, What {is} your occupation?</v>
      <v n="34">That ye shall say, Thy servants' trade hath been about cattle from our youth even until now, both we, {and} also our fathers: that ye may dwell in the land of Goshen; for every shepherd {is} an abomination unto the Egyptians.</v>
    </c>
